Charles Ives Rare and Non-Commercial Sound Recordings
Yale University Music Library
- Open reel tapes, Series VI
  - Ives Centenary Concert, undated; 1 (Box 114, Item barcode 39002038373602)
  - Ives; Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco; Peter Korn; Ernest Gold, 1963; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002038373628)
    Performers: Marni Nixon.
  - Ives; Varese, 1973 May 24; 1 (Box 114, Item barcode 39002038373610)
    Performers: New Haven Civic Orchestra; Gordon Emerson; Nicolas Slonimsky, conductor. Woolsey Hall.
  - In search of Charles Ives; documentary; tape 2 of 2, undated; 1 (Box 113, Item barcode 39002038373537)
  - Bamert: Mantrajana -- Brahms: Double Concerto -- Ives: Holiday Symphony (rehearsal), 1971 December 11; 1 (Box 113, Item barcode 39002038373529)
    Performers: Leopold Stokowski.
  - Yale Reports: Charles Ives' Theater Orchestra Music: Mr J Sinclair, 1974 June 23; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373651)
  - Yale Reports; Modern music and the debt to Charles Ives; part 1; James M. Drew, 1970 December 27; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373693)
  - Yale Reports; Modern music and the debt to Charles Ives; part 2; James M. Drew, 1971 January 3; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373685)
  - Charles Ives; Robert Schumann (side 1); Joseph Marx (side 2); Hugo Wolf (side 3); Herman Reutter (side 4); Town Hall, New York City reel #1, 1974; 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011007)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright, soprano; Hermann Reutter, piano.
    Pulled from The Howard and Helen Boatwright papers (MSS 93) Box 75 - June 2017.
  - Charles Ives; Robert Schumann (side 1); Joseph Marx (side 2); Hugo Wolf (side 3); Herman Reutter (side 4); Town Hall, New York City reel #1, 1974; 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126010991)
  - Charles Ives; Robert Schumann (side 1); Joseph Marx (side 2); Hugo Wolf (side 3); Herman Reutter (side 4); Town Hall, New York City reel #2, 1974; 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011015)
  - Thorne; Phelps; Charles Ives; Alice Tully Hall, New York City, 1974 June 5; 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011023)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright, soprano; Yehudi Wyner, piano.
  - Charles Ives Songs Concert at Jonathan Edwards College 1953, 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011106)
    Pulled from The Howard and Helen Boatwright papers (MSS 93) Box 75 - June 2017
  - Ives Songs 1969: Reel 3, 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011098)
  - Ives Songs 1969; Reel 4, 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011080)
  - Ives Songs 1969: Reel 5, 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011072)
  - Ives Songs 1969: Reel 6, 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011064)
  - Ives Songs 1969: Reel 7, 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011056)
  - Ives Songs 1969: Reel 8, 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011049)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright, soprano, John Kirkpatrick, piano.
  - Songs of Charles Ives; Sprague Memorial Hall, 1968 December 29; 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002126011031)
  - Ives Recording; Reel 2, 1969 November 18; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002126011130)
    Pulled from The Howard and Helen Boatwright papers (MSS 93) Box 76 - June 2017
  - Ives Recording; Reel 1, 1969 November 18; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002126011122)
    Pulled from The Howard and Helen Boatwright papers (MSS 93) Box 76 - June 2017.
  - Ives Songs; Reel 9, 1969; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002126011114)
  - Buxtehude; Ives; Copland; Howard Boatwright; Corneliu Gheorghiu; rehearsal performance at Ambassadors Residence, Bucharest, Romania, 1972; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002126011148)
    Pulled from The Howard and Helen Boatwright papers (MSS 93) Box 80 - June 2017.
  - Henry Purcell; John Blow; Charles Ives; Howard Boatwright; Grace Church, Utica, New York, 1971; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002126011155)
    Performers: Men and Boys Choir; Walter Hillsman, organist and Choirmaster; Helen Boatwright, soprano.
  - Ives Concert, 1974 March 3; 1 (Box 112, Item barcode 39002038373271)
    Performers: Yale Theater Orchestra.
  - Pej Takes; reel 7, undated; 1 (Box 113, Item barcode 39002038373560)
  - Pej Takes; reel 8, undated; 1 (Box 113, Item barcode 39002038373552)
  - Pej Takes; reel 9, undated; 1 (Box 113, Item barcode 39002038373545)
  - Pej Takes; reel 10, undated; 1 (Box 114, Item barcode 39002038373586)
  - Symphony No. 4, 1970 November 17; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373925)
    Performers: American Symphony Orchestra; Stokowski, conductor.
  - Symphony No. 3; Reel 1, 1969 November 2; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002128474781)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright and John Kirkpatrick (???)
    This item is part of of a separate collection - Richard C. Burns Archive of Overtone Records (MSS 104)
  - Symphony No. 3; Reel 2, 1969 November 2; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002128474799)
  - Symphony No. 3; Reel 3, 1969 November 2; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002128474807)
  - Yale Centennial Concert; Reel 1, 1954 November 5; 1 (Box 26, Item barcode 39002128474765)
  - Yale Centennial Concert; Reel 2, 1954 November 5; 1 (Box 26, Item barcode 39002128474773)
  - Cello Concerto; Saint-Saens/Ives Conversation, 1980 November 19; 1 (Box 58, Item barcode 39002126011247)
    This item is part of of a separate collection - Yale School of Music tapes (HSR 4)
  - Third Symphony (ed. Singleton), first performance of new edition -- Ragtime Dance No.3 (ed. Sinclair), premiere; Sprague Hall, 1976 February 25; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002128474815)
    Performers: Sinclair, conductor.
  - Ragtime Dance No.1 (ed. Sinclair), premiere, Sprague Hall, 04/22/1976 -- Three Places in New England (ed. Sinclair), first performance of new edition, Sprague Hall, 03/10/1979, 1976 April 22–1979 March 10; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002128474823)
    Performers: Chamber Orchestra of New England.
  - Sonata No. 2 "Concord", Recorded in Los Angeles, 09/24/1950; Aescylus and Sophocles -- Halloween -- Music on the Roof; Los Angeles, 05/13/1951, 1950 September 24; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002128474831)
    Performers: Frances Mullen.
  - Violin Sonatas 1-4 -- Decoration Day (A1), 1976 January 19; 1 (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013797)
    Performers: John Kirkpatrick, Daniel Stepner. Recorded in Sprague Memorial Hall. Presented by Yale School of Music. Also includes a work by Carl Ruggles entiteld Mood (about 1918?). Includes a copy of the concert program.
  - Violin Sonatas 1-4 -- Decoration Day (A2), 1976 January 19; 1 (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013789)
    Performers: John Kirkpatrick, Daniel Stepner. Recorded in Sprague Memorial Hall. Presented by Yale School of Music. Also includes a work by Carl Ruggles entiteld Mood (about 1918?).
  - Violin Sonatas 1-4 -- Decoration Day (A3), 1976 January 19; 1 (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013771)
  - Violin Sonatas 1-4 -- Decoration Day (A4), 1976 January 19; 1 (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013763)
- Rare commerical recordings, Series VII
  - Three Places in New England: I. The St. Gaudens' in Boston Common (Col. Shaw and his Colored Regiment) II. Putnam's Camp, Redding, Connecticut, III. from The Housatonic at Stockbridge, 1978; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013946)
    Performers: Saint Paul Chamber Orchestra; Dennis Russell Davies, cond. Record Label: Sound 80. Disc No. S80-DLR-101-A/B SPCO-622.
  - Trio für Violine, Violoncello und Klavier: I. Moderato II. TSIAJ-Presto-Allegro moderato III. Moderato con moto, 1988; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013938)
    Performers: Das Folkwang Klaviertrio (Pierre-Alain Chamot, violin; Thomas Dieker, violoncello; Susanne Maninger, klavier). Record Label: Outsider. Disc No. Outsider 110; LC 8517.
  - Largo for Clarinet, Violin, Piano, 1983; 4; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013920)
    Performers: Eduard Brunner, Gidon Kremer, Aloys Kontarsky. Record Label: Orfeo. Disc No. S 099 844 F. Live at the Lockenhaus Festival.
  - Piano Sonata No. 2 "Concord, Mass.", 1977; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013912)
    Performer: Ruth Duncan McDonald. Record Label: none. Disc No. none. Live at Wigmore Hall, London.
  - At the river, 1980; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013904)
    Performers: The Choir of Men, Boys And Girls of Trinity Church; James Litton, cond. and organist; Harold Pysher and Irene Willis, organists. Record Label: Gamut. Disc No. UT 7501.
  - Holidays Symphony: I. George Washington's Birthday II. Decoration Day III. The Fourth of July IV. Thanksgiving And/Or Forefather's Day, 1967–1969; 1; 10" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013896)
    Performers: Orchestra Sinfonica di Dallas; Donald Johanos. Record Label: iGM La Musica Moderna. Disc No. mm-1026.
  - "Country Band" March (arr. J.B. Sinclair), 1975; 2; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013870)
    Performers: Hartt Summer Youth Band; Donal A. Mattran, cond. Record Label: Disc No. HCO92575A/B.
  - Piano Sonata No. 2 "Concord Mass.": I. Emerson II. Hawthorne III. The Alcotts IV. Thoreau, 1984; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013862)
    Performer: Tom Plaunt. Record Label: McGill University. Disc No. 83018.
  - A Christmas Carol, 1985; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013854)
    Performers: Choral Guild of Atlanta; William Noll, cond. Record Label: Press Avant. Disc No. P 5002
  - Sonata No. 4 for Violin and Piano, 1986; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013847)
    Performers: Frank Almond, violin; Rojan da Silva, piano. Record Label: in russian. Disc No. C10 24625 006. VIII International Tchaikovsky Competition.
  - Pieces, 1981; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013839)
    Performers: in russian. Record Label: in russian. Disc No. C10-15369-70.
  - Variations on "America" (Introduction, Chorale, and 5 Variations), 1973; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013821)
    Performer: Robert Roubos. Record Label: The Wicks Organ Concert Series. Disc No. TS73-723/724.
  - String Quartet No. 1: I. Andante con moto II. Allegro III. Adagio cantabile IV. Allegro marziale, 1983; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013458)
    Performers: The Amici Quartet. Record Label: GSGC. Disc No. GSGC 2068.
  - Three-Page Sonata: I. Allegro moderato II. Andante - Adagio III. Allegro. March Time, 1981; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013466)
    Performer: William Naboré. Record Label: Pan. Disc No. Pan 130 032.
  - Country band march -- The swimmers -- Mists -- Charlie Rutlage -- Evening -- March II -- March III -- Overture and march: 1776 -- An old song deranged -- Gyp the Blood or Hearst!? -- Which is worst?! -- Remembrance -- Fugue in 4 keys on The shining shore -- Chromatimelodtune (previously recorded) -- Holiday quickstep., 1975; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013474)
    Performers: Yale Theater Orchestra; James Sinclair, cond. Record Label: Columbia. Disc No. M 32969. Edited or realized from the composer's manuscripts. or emendations by J. Sinclair, K. Singleton, and R. Kirkpatrick.
  - Set no. 1: The see'r. A lecture. The new river. Like a sick eagle. Calcium light night. Incantation (Allegretto sombreoso)--Tone roads no. 1.--Set no. 3: At sea (Adagio sostenuto). Luck and work. Premonitions.--From the steeples and the mountains.--The rainbow.--Ann Street.--Scherzo: Over the pavements.--From set no. 2: The Indians. The last reader.--Tone roads no. 3.--The pond.--All the way around and back.--Chromatimelodtune., 1970; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013813)
    Performers: Chamber orchestra; Gunther Schuller cond. Record Label: Columbia. Disc No. MS 7318.
  - Let there be light -- Psalm 14 -- Psalm 25 -- Psalm 54 -- Psalm 135 -- Walt Whitman -- Duty and Vita -- On the antipodes -- The last reader -- Luck and work -- Like a sick eagle -- Tolerance -- From the Incantation -- The pond -- At sea -- The children's hour -- The rainbow., 1970; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013805)
    Performers: Gregg Smith Singers; Columbia Symphony Orchestra; Columbia Chamber Ensemble; Gregg Smith, cond. Record Label: Columbia. Disc No. MS 7321.
  - Second Piano Sonata: Concord, Mass., 1840-1860, 1962; 1; 12" vinyl disc (Box 118, Item barcode 39002126013482)
    Performers: George Pappastavrou. Record Label: Composers Recordings, Inc. Disc No. CRI 150.